Shivank Chauhan 🚹 premium |





Key skills- Java, spring, SQL, hibernate, REST web services, spring security, spring boot, Kafka, design patterns, data structures and algos, micro services, agile, no sql.



Current Designation: Technical Lead Engineer Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: MakeMyTrip Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: java developer, spring, hibernate, rest web services, agile mythology, svn, perforce, maven, sql, spring

security, spring boot, algorithms, data structures, GIT, Kafka, NoSQL, MongoDB, Microservices

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

### Summary

Currently, working in Sapient and have 5 years and 10 months of experience in development and implementation of Java/J2EE projects following agile mythology.

Excellent Java development skills using Java 8, Spring boot, REST web services, Hibernate, Kafka.

Extensive development experience using OOPs, design pattern, data structured and algos.

Manage individual projects, including planning and monitoring of the work performed by other Programmer to the task.

Got value award 'SMART' and many appreciation awards and mails from client.

Track record of delivering quality Java/JEE based solutions in Banking, Logistics & Retail and in telecom domain.

Efficient analytical, problem-solving and decision-making skills. Work well under pressure.

Able to solve complex problems and provide working solutions.

## Work Experience

MakeMyTrip as Technical Lead Engineer Jul 2019 to Till Date

Lenskart as Senior Software Developer Jul 2018 to Jul 2019

Working in backend team of lenskart.com.

Sapient as Senior Software Developer Mar 2016 to Jul 2018

Working as a senior developer for RBS client on application LIMA - Limits and Excess Management System. Have developed LIMA application from scratch using java 8, Spring boot, Spring data repositories, REST web services, Hibernate and Kafka.

My role involves designing, coding, unit testing, code review and mentoring.

Amdocs as Senior Developer Oct 2014 to Dec 2015

EPP - Enterprise Payment Processing Project

Customer AT&T, Sprint and Metro Period Working from October, 2014

Domain Telecommunication

The product processes payments coming through different channels such as web, ivr etc. and made using different payment options such as credit cards, debit cards, ACH, paypal. Is completely PCI compliant and provides following functionalities:-

Product supports all kinds of payments such as anonymous pay, wallet pay, full and partial refund/chargeback, credit and conditional deposit payments.

Payments are processed either in one go as single phase or as two phase. Also they can be processed in online or offline mode. In offline mode payments are added to settlement groups to be processed later.

Basic steps for processing a payment involves, performing validations and fraud check, then auth/verify takes place during which money is either reserved or verification is done. Billing is informed for processing/creating bills and finally capture is done, in which money is charged or given to customer depending upon requirements.

Product also supports automatic retries if payment fails and auth and account cleanup jobs for removing the expired payments and accounts.

Requirement gathering and understanding the business requirements.

Brain storming in which different implementation approaches are discussed.

Coding and designing.

Regular interaction with team at different locations.

Technologies Java Spring, Hibernate, SQL **REST Web Services** 

Solution Environment JDK 1.8

Apache tomcat server.

Oracle Database.

Perforce as revision control and code collaborator for code reviews.

Maven as build tool.

Frameworks Spring, Hibernate

## Syntel as Advanced Software Engineer

May 2012 to Sep 2014

Project FedEx AMO Customer FedEx

Period jun-2012 to oct-2014

Domain Logistics

Description Fedex.com is official site of FedEx which is a GUI application. CXS (Customer Experience Service) are the group of application with similar architecture and provide business layer for fedex.com. There are 8 CXS applications (SHPC, CDAC, CMDC, RATC, USRC, PUDC, DOCC and GTIC). I am handling these CXS applications.

Below is a high level over view of how these application work-

Request comes from fedex.com or frontend using restful web services to CXS applications.

The request information is in JSON (Java Script Object notation). This request is converted in to java object using Spring

The role of CXS applications is to apply different validations and business logic, then if required CXS applications further interacts with FedEx FAST services using RMI or database using Hibernate.

Then finally, outputs are converted back to JSON and send to frontend application.

I am working as module lead in a team of 5.

I have responsibility for handling all the phases of software development for 8 CXS applications.

Regular interaction with client and onsite counterparts for gathering requirement and giving final development.

Assigning work to other resources.

**Technologies** Spring, Hibernate Restful Web Services Solution Environment **JDK** Oracle Weblogic Server Oracle Database. SVN for synchronizing code.

ANT for building and deploying applications.

Frameworks Spring, Hibernate .

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from rajasthan technical university in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

SCJP1.6-Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE6 Programmer, 2010

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
REST web services, Maven		5 Year(s) 8 Month(s)
Java, sql,Spring, Hibernate		5 Year(s) 8 Month(s)
BEA Web Logic, Tomcat		5 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Eclipse, NetBeans,SVN, perforce		5 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Linux and Windows		5 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

#### **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time